呼叫控制中心
Calling Cape Com. Cape Com.
这里是木星16号 可以进入第四号轨道吗？
This is Jupiter 16. Can you give a go for fourth orbit?
控制中心回答木星16号 可否证实氧气压力在范围内
Cape Com to Jupiter 16. Confirm 02 pressure is within limit.
收到 环境控制系统一切良好
Roger. It all looks good in the environmental control system.
好的 从这里看来一切良好 可以进入第四号轨道
OK. Everything looks good from here. You have a go for fourth orbit.
木星16号 收到
Jupiter 16. Roger.
我们已准备好太空漫步
Stowing all loose gear, ready for the EVA.
木星16号 准备好就开始太空漫步
Jupiter 16, this is Cape Com. Start your EVA any time you're ready.
你已练习过很多次太空漫步了
You have time in the other EVAs for experiments.
- 所以别停留太久 克里斯 - 好的
- So don't stay out too long, Chris. - OK, flight.
- 别担心 我们会依计划行事 - 收到
- Don't worry. We'll stick to plan. - Roger.
控制中心呼叫木星16号 开始倒数 我的仪器读数是437
Cape Com to Jupiter 16. On my mark it will be four plus three seven.
四 三 二 一 开始
Four, three, two, one, mark.
控制中心 我是克里斯 我已走出太空船 一切良好
Cape Com, this is Chris. I'm out. Everything looks OK.
很好
Good.
手动装置这次并没有失灵 我利用它出舱外 这次容易多了
The maneuvering unit is working this time. It makes things a lot easier.
控制中心呼叫夏威夷 这里是控制中心 请回答
Cape Com to Hawaii. This is flight control. Come in.
夏威夷 收到
Hawaii, roger.
夏威夷 这次太空漫步 将会在你们基地的上空进行
Hawaii, we expect to start EVA over your station on this pass.
夏威夷呼叫木星16号
Hawaii to Jupiter 16.
有个不明物体从船尾快速接近你 你看到吗？
There is an unidentified object closing on you fast from astern. Can you see it?
夏威夷 我们看不到 让我们查查太空船
Hawaii, we have nothing here. Hold while we check the space track.
夏威夷呼叫木星16号
Hawaii to Jupiter 16.
重复 夏威夷呼叫木星16号
Repeat, Hawaii to Jupiter 16.
从我们的观测器看到 有个不明物体快速接近
There is an unidentified object on our scope closing fast.
我看不到任何东西 你能给我方位吗？
We see nothing. Can you give me a bearing?
它从船尾快速的接近
Appears to be coming up fast from astern.
我看到它了
Hey, now I see it.
是另一艘太空船 重复 是另一艘太空船
It's another spacecraft. Repeat, it's another spacecraft!
- 它看来像只是经过吗？- 你的电讯断断续续 再说一次
- Does it look like a close pass? - You're breaking up. Say again.
- 它看来像只是经过吗？- 克里斯 发生了什么事
- Does it look like a close pass? - Chris, what's happening?
它向著我们飞来
It's coming right at us.
它的前端打开了 重复 它的前端打开了！
The front is opening up. I repeat, the front is opening up!
- 它向著我们飞来 - 快回去船舱里…
- It's coming right at us. - Chris, get back in. Get back in!
你听得到我吗？你的电讯断了
Do you read me? You're breaking up.
克里斯 发生什么事了？怎么了？
Chris, what's happening? What's happening?
夏威夷呼叫木星16号 听到吗？请回答
Hawaii to Jupiter 16. Hawaii to Jupiter 16. Are you receiving me? Come in, please.
我的生命线断了
My lead line! It's…
夏威夷呼叫木星16号 夏威夷呼叫木星16号
Hawaii to Jupiter 16. Hawaii to Jupiter 16.
你接收得到吗？请回答 通话完毕
Are you receiving me? Come in, please. Over.
休士顿？无线电通讯中断了 在观测器上也找不到它
Hello, Houston? We've lost radio contact. We've also lost him on the scope.
不明物体还在轨道上 通知所有基地密切追踪它
Unidentified object is still orbiting. Alert all stations and track him closely.
太可笑了 苏联政府竟然否认这件事跟他们有关
It is ridiculous for the Soviet government to deny responsibility.
苏联政府否认知道此事
The Soviet government denies all knowledge of this affair.
全世界都知道 我国是爱好和平的
The world knows we are a peace-loving people.
因此我通知各位二十天后
I hereby give notice that in 20 days' time.
美国打算发射另一艘太空船
the United States will launch her next spaceship into orbit.
我国政府吩咐我来通知各位
I am instructed to inform you.
任何妨碍这艘太空船的行动 将会被视为战争行为
that any interference with it will be regarded as an act of war.
我想请问有任何动机使得我们的俄国朋友
May I ask what motive our Russian friends would have.
希望毁灭美国的太空船
for wishing to destroy American spacecraft?
我国政府认为这是很明显的企图
My government sees this as nothing less than a blatant attempt.
为了军事目的而想完全控制太空
to gain complete and absolute control of space itself for military purposes.
我们不同意
We don't agree.
英国政府不认为…
Her Majesty's Government is not convinced.
那艘飞船来自苏联政府
that this intruder missile originated from Soviet Russia.
新加坡的雷达观测站
Our tracking station in Singapore.
探测到在日本海附近收到太空船的微弱回响
reported faint echoes of this craft coming down in the Sea of Japan area.
我建议各位把情报力量集中在该地区
Might I suggest this is where you should concentrate your intelligence forces?
首相要我向各位保证我们也打算这样做
The prime minister assures you that this is what we propose to do.
实际上 我们的情报员已在香港展开行动
As a matter of fact, our man in Hong Kong is working on it now.
为什么中国女孩尝起来 会与众不同？
Why do Chinese girls taste different from all other girls?
你认为我们比较好吗
You think we better, huh?
不 就是不同
No, just different.
就像北京烤鸭跟俄式鱼子酱不同 但我两者都爱
Like Peking duck is different from Russian caviar, but I love 'em both.
- 我提供给你最好的鸭 - 那真是太好了
- Darling, I give you very best duck. - That would be lovely.
我们共度了愉快的时光 我真的舍不得走
We've had some interesting times together, Ling. I'll be sorry to go.
守着门口
Check that door.
那张床
The bed.
- 我们来晚了 - 至少他是因工殉职
- We're too late. - Well, at least he died on the job.
他一定想死于此因
He'd have wanted it this way.
《007系列之雷霆谷》
在那眼睛闪烁的瞬间
"We shall not all sleep, but we shall all be changed,
在最后的号角声中
"in a moment, in the twinkling of an eye, at the last trump."
当号角响起 死者将是圣洁的
"For the trumpet shall sound and the dead shall be raised incorruptible,
我们都会改变
"and we shall all be changed."
因此把他的躯体交托给大海
"We therefore commit his body to the deep to be turned into corruption,
在大海释放他的时候 得到再生
"looking for the resurrection of the body when the sea shall give up her dead."
立正
Present!
鸣枪！
Fire!
- 打开 - 是的 长官
- Carry on. - Aye aye, sir.
- 请求允许登船 - 允许登船 谢谢你
- Request permission to come aboard, sir. - Permission granted.
- 带这名军官出去 - 是
- Take this officer aft. - Yes, sir.
一号 带她去045
Number One, take her up to 90 feet. Course 045.
是的 先生
Aye aye, sir.
- 你好 班霓 - 你最好马上进去
- Hello, Penny. - You'd better go right in.
你又迟到了 从你自己的丧礼来也迟到
You're late as usual. Even from your own funeral.
我们死人是没有时间观念的
We corpses have no sense of timing.
- 你可以进去了 先生 - 谢谢你 女士
- In you go… sir. - Thank you… ma'am.
- 请坐 007 - 谢谢长官
- Oh, sit down, 007. - Thank you, sir.
- 没有副作用吧？- 一点都没有
- No ill effects? - None at all, sir.
你现在已死了 或许你的一些老朋友会暂时不太注意你
Now you're dead, perhaps some of your old friends will pay less attention to you.
让你有多一点活动空间 你会需要的
Give you more elbow room. You'll need it, too.
这件事很严重 这也是我亲自来的原因 我想你已得到简报
This is the big one. That's why I'm out here myself. I take it you're fully briefed?
是的 我有一件事不明白
Yes, sir. But there's one thing I don't understand.
如果在新加坡的 雷达观测站没错…
If our tracking station is correct.
查知火箭没有降落在俄国 那它会降落在哪里？
about the rocket not landing in Russia, then where did it land?
我们估计是在日本
We assume it's Japan.
提醒你 这只是猜测 但首相要我们全力调查
This is pure guesswork, but the PM wants us to play it with everything we've got.
- 有做空中侦察吗？- 每一处都拍了照但没发现
- And the aerial reconnaissance? - Every inch photographed. Nothing.
日本有能力发射这样的火箭吗
Are the Japanese equipped to launch such a rocket?
- 我们不认为他们有 - 那谁能够呢
- We don't think so. - Then who else is?
你要在战争爆发前尽快找出是谁
That's what you've got to find out. And fast, before the real shooting starts.
这件事有可能导致全面战争
This damn thing could blow up into a full-scale war.
到达东京后 到这个地址找此人
When you get to Tokyo, go to that name and address.
- 我们的人员汉德森会跟你联络 - 汉德森
- Our man Henderson will contact you. - Henderson.
- 长官 我们正全速前进 - 好的
- Captain here, sir. We're under way. - Right.
- 没别的了 - 谢谢长官
- That's all. - Thank you, sir.
- 007？- 是
- 007? - Sir.
我们离美国发射另一艘太空船 只有三星期的时间 你知道吧
We've only three weeks till the Americans launch the next one. You know that?
情报说苏联太空船会更早发射
And my sources tell me the Russians are planning one even earlier than that.
- 因此要尽快行动 - 是的
- So move fast, 007. - Yes, sir.
那个女孩如何？
Oh, by the way, how was the girl?
- 哪个女孩？- 我们替你安排的中国女孩
- Which girl? - The Chinese one we fixed you up with.
- 再过五分钟我便可知道 - 她不知道她错过了什么
- Another five minutes, I'd have found out. - Hm. She'll never know what she missed.
钱班霓小姐
Miss Moneypenny?
把日本情报局的暗号告诉他
Give 007 the password we've agreed with Japanese SIS.
好的
Yes, sir.
我们设法想一个你不会忘记的
We tried to think of something that you wouldn't forget.
是什么？
Yes?
我爱你
"I love you."
你重复一次 以免你不知道
Repeat it, please, to make sure you get it.
放心 我知道 谢谢
Don't worry, I get it. Sayonara.
詹姆斯 祝你好运
James? Good luck.
日语速成 你可能需要的
Instant Japanese. You may need it.
你忘了我在剑桥的东方语言科拿第一名
You forget, I took a first in oriental languages at Cambridge.
准备装上
Stand by to load.
准备发射
Lift to the launch.
发射
Fire.
这是你的门票
This is your ticket.
谢谢
Thank you.
我爱你
I love you.
我的车就在附近
I have a car nearby.
- 你建议我们去哪里？- 我知道有一间僻静的旅馆
- Oh? Where do you suggest we go? - I know a quiet hotel.
- 然后呢？- 你的朋友在哪里等你？
- And? - Where your friend is waiting.
汉德森先生
Mr. Henderson.
他无法亲自来吗？
Wasn't Mr. Henderson able to come himself?
- 我想不能 - 为什么？
- I suppose not. - Why?
他没说
He didn't say.
该去旅馆了
Well, I think it's about hotel-time.
你帮汉德森工作多久了
How long have you been working for Henderson?
久到知道不该跟陌生人讨论此事
Long enough to learn not to discuss such matters with strangers.
- 汉德森先生在等你 - 你不跟我一起进去吗？
- Mr. Henderson's waiting for you. - You're not coming in with me?
汉德森先生想单独见你
Mr. Henderson would like to see you alone.
请进来
Do come in.
你是汉德森先生
Mr. Henderson?
在下正是
At your service.
我相信你想问我一些问题
I believe you wanted to ask me some questions.
没错 请原谅
Yes. Excuse me.
- 谢谢 - 幸好你没敲错腿
- Thank you. - I'm glad you got it right.
1942年我在新加坡失掉那条腿
I lost that in Singapore in '42.
请原谅我这种混合式的装潢
Oh, you must excuse this rather odd mixture of styles,
我不想变得完全日本化
but I refuse to go entirely Japanese.
我很喜欢这些古董
Very fond of some of these old things.
- 你没有来过日本？- 从没有过
- You've never been to Japan before? - No, never.
我已经在这里居住了…
I myself have lived here for, er…
二十八年 现在才开始熟悉环境
28 years. And I'm just beginning to know my way about.
- 你最重要的联络人是田中 - 田中？
- Your most vital contact will be Tanaka. - Tanaka?
他是日本情报局的主管
He's head of the Japanese secret service.
他的身分是日本的最高机密
And his identity is the most closely guarded secret in Japan.
我什么时候可以见他？
When can I see him?
- 你今晚就可以见老虎 - 老虎？
- You can see Tiger tonight. - "Tiger?"
他的好朋友是这样称呼他的
His closest friends are permitted to call him that.
- 你自己有线索吗？- 我有
- Do you have any leads of your own? - Yes, I do.
那是搅拌的 不是摇的 你喜欢这样 是不是？
That's stirred, not shaken. That was right, wasn't it?
太好了 干杯 干杯
Perfect. Cheers.
俄国的伏特加酒 非常好
Russian vodka. Well done.
俄国大使馆的警卫给我的
I get it from the doorman at the Russian embassy.
当然还有其他东西
Amongst certain other things.
我认为…
Now, look.
伦敦方面的推论是正确的 飞弹是由这里发射的
I think London's theory about the missile being fired from this country is right.
我不知道地点和方法 也不知道是谁做的
I don't know how or where, and don't ask me who's doing it either.
但是我有预感… 幕后有外国势力在操纵
But, er… I have a fairly shrewd idea that a major foreign power is behind it all.
俄国和日本以外的势力？
You mean apart from Russia and Japan?
我肯定不是俄国
Oh, it's not Russia, old boy. I'm sure of that.
也不是日本
It's not Japan either.
虽然有一间日本的大企业
Although a large Japanese industrial concern is…
晚安
Good evening.
干杯
Cheers.
伏特加
Siamese vodka?
快上车！
Get in, quick!
到底是怎么一回事？
Now, what the hell's the score?
什么意思？我是来帮助你的
What do you mean? My job is to help you.
- 就像你帮助汉德森一样？- 我要带你去一个安全的地方
- Like you helped Henderson? - I'm taking you to a place of safety.
不 这次换我来带你 我要知道一些资料 现在就要
No, this time I'm taking you. I want some information now.
- 我没有资料给你 - 待会就知道 慢一点
- I have no information to give you. - We'll soon see about that. Slow down.
欢迎
Welcome.
欢迎来到日本 邦德先生
Welcome to Japan, Mr. Bond.
很高兴终于跟你见面
It is a great pleasure to meet you at last.
目前为止 你对我们国家的印象如何？
And how do you like our country so far?
我有点失望 这么容易就能引你来这里
I am a trifle disappointed at the ease with which I could pull you in.
很久以前 我母亲就告诉我
The one thing my honorable mother taught me long ago.
千万别坐上陌生女子的车
was never to get into a car with a strange girl.
但你会跟女人做任何事情
But you, I'm afraid, will get into anything with any girl.
对一个死人来说 你倒生龙活虎
I must say, you have a lot of energy for a dead man, Mr. Bond.
你是詹姆斯邦德吧？
You are James Bond, aren't you?
我很高兴认识你 我真的很高兴
I am so very pleased to meet you, Bond-san. I really am.
请容我自我介绍
Permit me to introduce myself.
我是田中 请叫我老虎
My name is Tanaka. Please call me Tiger.
如果你是田中 那你对我感觉如何？
If you're Tanaka, how do you feel about me?
我爱你
I… love you.
很高兴能弄清楚你的身分
I'm glad we got that out of the way.
我希望你能尽快检验这些
I'd like you to examine these as soon as possible.
它们是从大里的保险箱取出来的
They're from Osato's safe.
海军商店的订货单 五百公斤牛油 五十桶熏咸鲑鱼
This is an order for naval stores. 500 kilos of butter, 50 containers of lox.
- 那是什么？- 是美国的腌鲑鱼
- What is lox? - An American name for smoked salmon.
但也是液态氧的名字 可以用作火箭燃料
But it's also the technical name for liquid oxygen, which makes rocket fuel.
- 非常有趣 - 嗯
- Very interesting. - Yes.
我们走吧
We must go.
出去比进来时庄重多了
The journey out will be more dignified than the journey in.
那一点都不困难
That wouldn't be difficult.
- 我想放大那张底片 - 没问题
- I'd like that negative enlarged. All right? - OK.
我的私人火车 我从不在东京街上走
My private train. I never travel in the streets of Tokyo.
以我的地位 这样是很不智的
In my position, it would be most unwise.
非常方便
Very convenient.
相信M在伦敦也是这样的
I imagine that your Mr. M in London has a similar arrangement.
M？是的 当然
M? Oh, yes, but of course.
开白色跑车的女子是我们的人
Then the girl in the white sports car's one of us.
- 明子？是 - 她非常能干
- Aki? Yes. - Very competent.
你喜欢日本清酒吗 还是伏特加马汀尼？
Do you like Japanese sake, Mr. Bond, or would you prefer vodka martini?
我喜欢清酒
Oh, no, I like sake.
尤其是温度适中的
Especially when it's served at the correct temperature.
华氏98.4度 就像现在这样
98.4?Fahrenheit, like this is.
以欧洲人来说 你非常讲究
For a European, you are exceptionally cultivated.
- 我们来看你发现的照片 - 好
- We'll see the photograph you found. - Good.
一条船跟一片地 有可能是任何地方
Just a ship and a strip of land. It could be anywhere.
我的手下在照片中发现一个微粒 放大！
My men found a microdot on the paper. Enlarge!
它说：「美国女游客…从船上拍到的」
It says, "Photograph taken by female American tourist from coastal vessel."
「作为一般的防范 她给杀害了」
"The woman has been liquidated as a routine precaution."
- 能再看一次吗？- 当然可以
- Can we see the photograph again? - Of course.
他们因为一张照片 而杀了一个无辜的游客
So they killed an innocent tourist for taking this?
能再放大点吗？
Can you make it bigger?
宁波
Ning-Po.
查查宁波号的详尽资料
Check motor vessel Ning-Po. Full details.
它最近的行踪及目前的地点
All recent movements and present whereabouts.
- 左边的是什么？- 集中在左边
- What's that on the left? - Focus on the left.
潜水女孩
Aha. Ama. Diving girls.
- 你能认出该海岸吗？- 有时间便可以
- Can you identify that coastline? - Given time, yes.
- 谁是大里化工的首脑 - 大里先生
- Who is the head of Osato Chemicals? - Mr. Osato.
- 可否替我安排明天见他？- 可以
- Can you arrange a meeting tomorrow? - Of course.
但今晚把这儿当作自个儿家 包括我的财产
But tonight, consider my house yours. Including all of my possessions, naturally.
现在来洗一个文明浴吧
My friend, now you take your first civilized bath.
是吗？我喜欢这里的水管装置
Really? Well, I like the plumbing.
你把自己交给她们就好了
Place yourself entirely in their hands, my dear Bond-san.
第一规则
Rule number one…
别人可代劳时 千万别亲自动手
is never do anything for yourself when someone else can do it for you.
- 第二呢？- 第二规则…
- And number two? - Rule number two…
在日本 一切以男人为先 女人次之
In Japan, men always come first. Women come second.
我可能会在这儿退休
I might just retire to here.
英国女人可永远不会这么做
Your English girls would never perform this simple service.
我认识有一两个会这么做
I think I know one or two who might get round to it.
是钱班霓小姐吧？
Miss Moneypenny, perhaps?
我们和你们一样也有情报的
We have our sources, Bond-san, just like you.
别把肥皂弄进我眼里好吗？
Don't get the soap in my eye, will you?
你知道你有什么令她们著迷吗？
You know what it is about you that fascinates them?
是你的胸毛 日本男人全都皮光肉滑
It's the hair on your chest. Japanese men all have beautiful bare skin.
日本的谚语说：「鸟儿不在秃树上筑巢」
Japanese proverb say, "Bird never make nest in bare tree."
若汉德森的理论正确
If Henderson's theory is right,
外国势力为何在日本发射飞弹
why would a foreign power want to launch missiles from Japan?
因为若被人发现 他们可否认一切
Because if ever they were discovered, they could deny responsibility.
尤其是私人组织做的
Especially if some private organization's doing the work.
- 大里？- 有可能
- Osato? - Perhaps.
大里是日本的大企业家之一
Mr. Osato is one of the greatest industrialists in Japan.
- 他只是用来掩护的 - 谁有这势力？
- No, he's merely a front. - Who is big enough?
- 魔鬼党 - 有可能
- SPECTER. - Could be.
按摩时间到 你选哪一个
Now, massage. Which girl do you select?
- 我选这位老太太吧 - 好选择 她非常性感
- I'll just settle for this little old lady here. - Good choice. She's very sexyful.
上次我是在香港被按摩
The last time someone gave me a massage was in Hong Kong.
可惜要中途停止
But unfortunately we had to cut it short.
被几个无礼的枪手打扰了
We were rudely interrupted by a couple of gunmen.
因此无法完成
So we never got around to finishing it.
这次我们可以完成
This time, you shall finish it.
明子
Aki.
今晚没人会骚扰你
No one will disturb you tonight.
我很高兴能在你底下替你服务
I think I will enjoy very much serving under you.
- 费雪先生 - 嗯
- Mr. Fisher? - Yes.
- 请往这边走 - 谢谢
- This way, please. - Thank you.
请进 费雪先生 大里先生马上就到 请你稍等
Please come in, Mr. Fisher. Mr. Osato is expecting you.
谢谢
Thank you.
你来早了三分半钟 请坐
You are 3? minutes early. Please be seated.
- 你好 费雪先生 - 你好
- How do you do, Mr. Fisher? - How do you do?
这是布兰特小姐 是我的私人秘书
Miss Brandt, my confidential secretary.
- 你好 - 你好
- Hello. - Hello.
- 你要喝杯香槟吗？- 不 谢谢 太早了
- May we offer you some champagne? - No, thank you. It's too early for me.
- 你确定？- 我确定
- You're quite sure? - Quite sure.
我总是在早上喝一杯 你应该试试
I always take a glass in the morning. You should try it.
- 对肝不好 不是吗？- 胡说 能让你整天都有活力
- It's bad for your liver, isn't it? - Nonsense. It adds a sparkle to the day.
当然
I'm sure it does.
费雪先生 59年的酒 你确定不来一杯
A Dom Pignon '59, Mr. Fisher. Are you really sure you won't change your mind?
- 好吧 既然你坚持 - 请坐 费雪先生 谢谢
- Well, if you insist. - Please be seated, Mr. Fisher.
你是帝国化工新来的董事？
So, you are the new managing director of Empire Chemicals?
- 那威廉森呢？- 威廉森
- What happened to Williamson? - Williamson?
是的 他是突然死亡
Ah, yes. He died rather suddenly, poor chap.
是什么原因？
Ah, so. From what?
- 他在工作时跌进了粉碎机 - 哦 原来啊…
- He fell into a pulverizer at the works. - Ah, so.
多可怕
How shocking.
- 很光荣的 - 没错
- A very honorable death, all the same. - Very.
他在公司很受到敬重
He gained great face with the company.
希望你不要冒险
I hope you are not taking any risks yourself, Mr. Fisher.
我 我从不冒险
Me? I never take any risks.
请你原谅我这么说
You forgive me for saying so, but, uh…
我认为你现在就在冒险
I think you are taking one now.
- 是吗？- 是
- I am? - Mm-hm.
你应该戒烟 抽烟会对你的肺造成损害
You should give up smoking. Cigarettes are very bad for your chest.
大里先生非常相信这点
Mr. Osato believes in a healthy chest.
真的？
Really?
现在 你得告诉我 我能为你做什么
Now, then, you must tell me what I can do for you.
我们想买大量的酵素…
We're interested in the bulk-buying of fermentation chemicals.
味精和抗坏血酸
Monosodium glutamate and ascorbic acid.
- 你需要制造执照吗？- 是的 非常需要
- You'd like a license to manufacture? - Yes, very much.
我会要求我的销售部经理 尽快为你附上估价单
So, I'll have my sales manager get quotations and delivery dates for you.
我们今天晚点会在旅馆联络你
We'll contact you later today at your hotel.
- 你住在哪间饭店？- 希尔顿
- Which hotel are you staying at? - The Hilton.
再见 费雪先生
Goodbye, Mr. Fisher.
- 很高兴认识你 - 我也很高兴认识你
- A pleasure to meet you. - A pleasure to meet you, too.
- 再见 布兰特小姐 - 再见 费雪先生
- Goodbye, Miss Brandt. - Goodbye, Mr. Fisher.
杀了他
Kill him.
蹲下！
Get down!
这里是294 老虎请回答
294 here. Tiger, immediate.
294请说
Come in, 294.
007在我旁边 我们正被一群 开黑色轿车的枪手追杀
Zero-zero is with me. We are being chased by gunmen in black sedan.
我向著南面的二号高速公路走 请按照以往的安排
I'm heading south for Highway Two. Arrange usual reception, please.
- 日本人办事的能力不错吧？- 沧海一粟
- How's that for Japanese efficiency? - Just a drop in the ocean.
- 007？- 是 老虎
- Zero-zero? - Yes, Tiger.
宁波号属于大里化工的
Motor vessel "Ning-Po" is owned by Osato Chemicals.
- 继续说 - 它正在神户港口装货
- That fits. Go on. - Vessel at present loading in Kobe docks.
今天下午五点会开往上海
Sailing for Shanghai at 5 p.m. this afternoon.
建议你立刻去神户探查
Suggest you proceed Kobe immediately to look her over.
- 我们来的及吗 - 可以 时间刚刚好
- Can we make it? - Yes, just.
立刻前往神户港口 老虎 联络M
Proceeding immediately, Kobe docks. Tiger, contact M.
要他送小娜莉来这里 重复 小娜莉
Tell him to send Little Nellie. Repeat, Little Nellie.
建议她父亲跟她随行
Suggest she be accompanied by her father.
- 非常紧急 明白吗？- 明白
- Most urgent. Understood? - Understood.
（上海 宁波号）
冷凝的液态氧
Condensation: ice-cold. Liquid oxygen.
离开这里 联络田中
Get out of here. Contact Tanaka.
- 我不离开你 - 不管船只开到哪里 都要盯著这艘船
- I'm not leaving you. - Tell him to keep that ship shadowed.
马上走
Go now.
带他去11号那里
Take him to Number 11.
- 叫醒他 - 你够了没
- Wake him up. - Are you finished?
我在哪里？
Where am I?
你在宁波号上 我的舱房内
You're in my cabin on the Ning-Po.
我来处理他 你们出去等 关上门
Leave him to me now. Wait in there. And shut the door.
我捉到你了
I've got you now.
好好享受
Well, enjoy yourself.
- 你为谁工作？- 帝国化工
- Who are you working for? - Empire Chemicals, you know that.
- 他们都随身带枪的吗？- 是的 当他们出国时
- Do all their people carry guns? - When they're abroad, yes.
你为什么在港口查探
And why were you snooping around the docks?
我喜欢船 我以前是船员
I like ships and I used to be a sailor.
你说谎
You are a liar.
- 你知道这是什么吗？- 我宁愿不知道
- Do you know what this is? - I'd rather not.
美容科医生称它为皮刀
Plastic surgeons call it a dermatome.
他们用它来割开皮肤
They use it to slice off skin.
我希望你不要逼我使用它
I hope you won't force me to use it.
你这么好的女孩 在这种地方做什么？
Now, what's a nice girl like you doing in a place like this?
- 我有话要说 - 是什么？
- I have a confession to make. - What?
实际上 我是个间谍
Actually, I'm a spy.
我知道
I know that.
你应该知道 商业机密是很值钱的
I suppose you know that industrial secrets are big business?
呃
Mm-hm.
我已偷了大里制造味精的方法
Well, I've stolen Osato's new process for making monosodium glutamate.
而且…
And, er…
那方法价值三十万美元
Well, it's worth $300, 000.
所以呢？
So?
如果你帮我逃回东京 我会跟你平分
I'll split it with you if you'll get me out of here and back to Tokyo.
听起来不错
That's a nice offer.
- 如何？- 我恐怕得拒绝
- How about it? - I'm afraid not.
为什么？
Why?
大里会杀了我
Osato would kill me.
我们可以明天就飞去欧洲
We could fly to Europe tomorrow, you and I.
我为英国而做的事
The things I do for England.
你今晚在东京需要严密的保护
You are going to need some very close protection tonight in Tokyo,
因为他们会来抓你
because… well, that's when they'll try and get at you.
- 你需要最好的保镖 - 你推荐谁？
- You'll need the best man we've got. - And who do you suggest?
我本人
Well, me.
我恐怕今晚另有约会
I'm afraid I have another appointment tonight, Mr. Fisher.
我很舍不得离开你 但我必须要走了
I'm awfully sorry to leave you, but I have to get off.
我已告诉过你 追女孩子会给你带来麻烦
Chasing girls will be the end of you, Bond-san. I told you before.
他并没有追她 他是为了让我逃走
He didn't chase her. He did it so I could get away.
他才不会碰那么可怕的女人 你不会 对吧？
He wouldn't touch that horrible girl. You wouldn't, would you?
我当然不会 有进展吗？
Oh, heaven forbid. Any progress?
有 我们已查出照片上的海岸
Yes. We have identified the coastline in the photograph.
是一个叫松江的小岛 就在神户跟上海之间
It is an island called Matsu, on the direct route between Kobe and Shanghai.
我们用直升机跟踪著宁波号
We shadowed the Ning-Po in a helicopter.
- 它停靠在那个小岛吗？- 没错
- Did it stop at the island? - I think so.
那天晚上很暗 不太看得见它
It was a very dark night. Impossible to see her all the time.
但我们知道它停靠在某处 你看这个
But we know she stopped somewhere. Look at these.
这张是我们昨晚照的
That one we took last night.
这张是今天早上照的
And that one, early this morning.
- 注意看它的水位 - 你说的对
- Notice, please, the water line. - You're right.
这张装满了货 这张却是空船
Fully laden here and empty here.
我现在要去那个岛看看
I want to take a fast look at the island.
- 小娜莉到达了没有？- 到了 她的父亲也来了
- Has Little Nellie arrived yet? - Yes. And her father.
欢迎到日本 老爸 我的小娜莉准备好了吗？
Welcome to Japan, Dad. Is my little girl hot and ready?
我飞了一段又长又累 又毫无目的旅途
Look, 007, I've had a long and tiring journey, probably to no purpose.
没有心情听你这些幼稚的嘲弄
I'm in no mood for your juvenile quips.
我很好奇 小娜莉是什么？
I have much curiosity, Bond-san. What is Little Nellie?
她是个又棒又小又快的女孩
Oh, she's a wonderful girl. Very small, quite fast.
能为你做任何事
Can do anything. Just your type.
- 一架玩具直升机 - 它绝对不是玩具 你会知道的
- A toy helicopter? - No, it's certainly not a toy. You'll see.
自从你上次用过后 我们又改进了它 我会告诉你如何使用
We made some improvements since you used her last. I'll give you the drill.
这是给小孩子坐的 别用它 用我的直升机
This can only be for children. Don't use it, Bond-san. Take my helicopter instead.
对 现在仔细听好
Right. Now pay attention.
- 两支固定的机关枪 - 射程有多远？
- Two machine guns, fixed. - Synchronized to what?
一百码 配有燃烧弹和高性能炸药
100 yards, using incendiaries and high explosives.
两支向前发射的火箭炮
Two rocket launchers, forward-firing on either side.
很好
Fine.
这是空对空探热导弹 一分钟六十英里
Now, these fire heat-seeking, air-to-air missiles. 60 a minute.
很好
Good.
两支向后发射的喷火枪
Flame guns. Two of 'em, firing astern.
- 射程多远？- 八十码
- What range? - 80 yards.
在它们旁边有两个烟雾喷射器
Two smoke ejectors next door to them.
航空地雷 要记得 飞在目标的正上方才能使用 就这么多
Aerial mines. Use them only when directly above target. That's about the lot, I think.
- 剩下的你都知道了吧 - 知道
- You know the rest, don't you? - Yes.
摄影机
Cine camera.
- 田中 收听410兆赫的频道 - 祝你好运
- Tanaka, listen in on 410 megacycles. - Good luck, Bond-san.
- 我一飞到小岛就会联络你 - 好的 小心
- I'll contact you when I reach the island. - Be careful, Bond-san.
基地一号 我正飞过小岛 除了看到渔村以外 没什么可报告
Hello, Base One. I'm over the island. Have seen the fishing village. Nothing to report.
收到 我们会继续收听
We'll keep listening.
基地一号 这里除了火山没别的
Hello, Base One. There's nothing here but volcanoes.
明白 继续
Understood. Carry on.
- 基地一号 - 我们正在听
- Hello, Base One. - Listening.
小娜莉受到热烈的欢迎 四个大汉刚对她进行骚扰
Little Nellie got a hot reception. Four big-shots made improper advances.
但她已成功的击退了敌人
But she defended her honor with great success.
- 现在正在回家 - 别回家
- Heading for home. - Do not come home, Bond-san.
苏联快要发射太空船 飞往4.6度航线 等待指示
Russian space shot imminent. Proceed vector 4-6 degrees and await instructions.
- 明白吗？- 收到
- Understood? - Roger and out.
离开降落区
Clear the area. Clear the area.
准备迎接
Prepare for reception.
雷达讯号已经完全中断
Radar blackout is now complete.
莫斯科电台已经说是我们做的
Moscow radio's already saying that we did it.
总统将在下午两点召开新闻发表会 否认此事和我们有关
The president's called a press conference. He'll deny we had anything to do with it.
- 但我们可以证明吗？- 当然不可以
- But can we prove it? - Of course we can't.
不会有人相信俄国自毁太空船
The world isn't gonna believe the Russians did it.
他们会藉机击落我们的木星号
They'll use the excuse to shoot down our next Jupiter.
休士顿通知华府 我们追踪了它一个轨道 后来它失去了踪影
Houston to Washington. We followed him for one orbit, now he's off the screen.
那意味著它正在降落
That means he's coming down.
- 是的 但在哪里？- 一定是在苏联的某个地方
- Yeah, but where? - Some place in Russia. It has to be.
英国人说在日本是荒谬的
The British theory about Japan is nonsense.
- 别提日本了 - 我同意
- Forget Japan. - I agree.
我们每英寸地方都拍了照片
We've rephotographed every square inch.
抽气扇全力开动 开启所有空气输送管
Ventilator fans to full power. Open all air ducts.
可以安全进入 所有人员就位
Area safe to enter. All crews to stations.
所有空气输送管回复正常
All air ducts to normal.
所有空气输送管开启
Air ducts opened.
- 关闭火山口 - 关闭火山口
- Close crater. - Closing crater.
武装守卫站岗
Fire guards to stations.
抽气扇回复正常 打开百叶窗
Ventilator fans to normal. Open shutters.
迎接完成
Reception complete.
取出被掳的太空船
Withdraw captive spaceship.
警卫就位
Guards to stations.
- 带走犯人 - 带走犯人
- Remove the prisoners. - Remove the prisoners.
我会在房间里
I shall be in my apartment.
可能稍后会找你们
I may send for you later.
恭喜你们 你们的仪器很先进
I must congratulate you, gentlemen, upon your superb equipment.
我们也恭喜你们计划成功
We congratulate you, sir, upon the way you handle it.
我们的客户至目前为止 仍感满意吧？
Our clients are satisfied with the progress so far?
- 我国政府很满意 - 很好
- My government is quite satisfied. - Good.
我的食人鱼很饿了
You will see that my piranha fish get very hungry.
它们能在三十秒内吃掉一个人
They can strip a man to the bone in 30 seconds.
我要你们把一亿元的黄金
I have decided to ask for a little money in advance.I want the sum of 100 million dollars in gold bullion.
存进我在布宜诺斯艾利斯的户口
deposited in our account in Buenos Aires.
我们的协议说好
Our agreement states clearly that no money should be paid.
美俄两国开战后才付钱
until war has broken out between Russia and the United States.
- 这简直是勒索 - 勒索是我的工作
- This is extortion. - Extortion is my business.
你们考虑一下吧 我很忙
Go and think it over, gentlemen. I'm busy.
大里跟11号马上进来
Osato and Number 11, report now.
那天有位不知名的英国人 到你办公室
An unknown Englishman was in your office the other day.
是的
Correct, Number One.
- 你知道这是什么手枪吗？- 华达PPK枪
- Do you know what gun this is? - Walther PPK.
只有一个人用这种手枪
Only one person we know uses this sort of gun.
詹姆斯邦德
James Bond.
- 但是邦德已经死了 - 报纸也刊登了
- But Bond is dead. - It was in all the newspapers.
胡说八道 邦德还活着
Rubbish. Bond is alive.
除非你已杀了他 大里先生
Unless you killed him, Mr. Osato?
别告诉我你让他逃走了
Don't tell me you let him go.
我已下令要11号杀了他
I gave Number 11 the strictest orders to eliminate him.
- 她有吗？- 她失败了
- And did she? - She failed.
你应该亲自下手 你有很多机会
You should have killed him yourself. You had plenty of opportunity.
这个组织不会容忍失败
This organization does not tolerate failure.
- 我知道 但… - 走吧
- I know, but you see… - Go.
还不走？
Well?
啊！
Aaargh!
大里！
Osato!
马上杀了邦德
Kill Bond! Now!
是的 一号
Yes, Number One. Yes. Yes, yes.
- 你好 - 外太空来的坏消息
- Hello. - Bad news from outer space.
我听说了 俄国政府正在指责美国
Yes, I heard it. Now the Russians are accusing the Americans.
- 下次便会开战了 - 我们要到火山去
- Next time it will be war. - We have to get down to those volcanoes.
我同意
I agree.
也需要一流的人手陪同
We'll also need a company of first-rate men.
- 你在这里有突击队吗？- 我有更好的
- Do you have any commandos here? - I have much, much better.
是忍者 这是高度机密
Ninjas. Top-secret, Bond-san.
这是我的忍者训练学校
This is my ninja training school.
- 忍者？- 神出鬼没 攻其不备
- Ninjas? - The art of concealment and surprise.
这可训练出极快的反应
This must develop very fast reflex actions.
还有意志力
And spiritual strength.
现在去看现代的忍者
Now we will see some modern ninjas.
我的计划是 我在岛上建立基地
My plan is this. I make a base on the Ama island.
一百名忍者会潜入岛上 假扮成工人跟渔夫
100 of my ninjas will slide in unseen. They will be workers and fishermen.
- 那我呢？- 待会儿再说
- What about me? - Later.
现在 你应该对这些有兴趣
But for the moment, these will interest you.
火箭枪 威力强大
Rocket guns. Very powerful.
后面的小孔是喷射推进
See the little holes in the back for jet propulsion?
- 很不错的枪 - 全都是火箭枪
- It's a fine gun. - All rocket guns.
这是特别的小火箭
This is our special baby rocket.
对抽太多烟的人非常有用
It's very useful for people who smoke too many cigarettes, like you.
- 三十码内百发百中 - 很精巧
- Accurate up to 30 yards. - Very neat.
这支香烟可以救你一命
It can save your life, this cigarette.
你的语气跟广告很像
You sound like a commercial.
- 对我有什么安排？- 首先 你要成为日本人
- Now, what's the plan for me? - First, you become a Japanese.
其次 你要努力练习成为忍者
Second, you train hard and quickly to become a ninja like us.
最后 为了掩人耳目 你要娶老婆
And third, to give you extra-special cover, you take a wife.
很可惜 不可能
Regretfully impossible.
你要娶一个当地的海女
You must marry Ama girl. One who is known on the island.
- 她漂亮吗？- 她跟母猪一样丑
- Is she pretty? - She has a face like a pig.
- 去你的鬼主意 - 但这是职责所在
- To hell with that idea. - But this is duty.
我所选的女子是我的情报员 但首先 你要成为日本人
The girl I have chosen is an agent of mine. But first, you must become Japanese.
为何不是只染外露的部位？
Why don't you just dye the parts that show?
- 晚上好 - 晚上好
- Konbanwa. - Konbanwa.
老虎说 从现在开始 你要做事日本化
Tiger said, from now on, you must do everything Japanese-style.
所有的事吗？
Everything?
老虎真好
Good for Tiger.
我…
I'm…
I… I…
- 明子 - 我…
- Aki. - I'm…
她死了
She's dead.
被毒死了
Poisoned.
老虎 我们必须到岛上去
Tiger, we must get to that island.
你还没准备好 再多等两天
You're almost ready. Just two more days' training.
- 你杀了他 - 他想杀我
- You killed him. - Yeah, he tried to kill me.
- 这个是外来的陌生人 - 我们能离开这里真的很幸运
- This man is a stranger from outside. - It's lucky we're getting out of here.
明天你将变成卑微的日本工人 有个谦恭的日本太太
Tomorrow you will be a poor Japanese worker with a humble Japanese wife.
是的 她跟母猪一样丑
Yeah, with a face like a pig.
我的手下已在岛上 遍布全岛
My men are already ashore, all over the island.
我们只剩四天 没有多少时间
We have four days left. It is not much time.
这是我家
This is my house.
我的朋友已帮我们准备了食物
My friend has made us some food.
- 你独自住在这里？- 是的 我的父母都去世了
- Do you live here alone? - Yes. My parents are dead.
请坐
Sit down, please.
生蠔
Oysters.
- 这里只有一个房间是的 - 那是你的床
- Is this the only room there is? - Yes. That is your bed.
我睡在那儿
I shall sleep over there.
我们已结婚了
We're supposed to be married.
请想清楚 你给祭司的名字是假的
Think again, please. You gave false name to priest.
没错 但是我们要逼真点 我们正在度蜜月
Yes, but we must keep up appearances. We're on our honeymoon.
没有蜜月 这是任务
No honeymoon. This is business.
那我不需要这些了
Well, I won't need these.
- 邦德？- 怎么了
- Bond-san? - What's wrong?
美国人改变了发射日期 他们已开始倒数
The Americans changed the launching date. The countdown has already started.
总统已在电视上 对俄国提出最后警告
The president has given a last warning to the Russians.
- 它何时会发射？- 日本时间 今天半夜
- When does it go up? - Tonight. Midnight, our time.
- 你的手下有搜查全岛了吗？- 没有任何线索
- Did your men search the island? - Yes. There is nothing except volcanoes.
除了火山以外一切都很正常 没事发生
Everything is so normal around here. Nothing happens.
发生了一件奇怪的事 昨天一个海女划船进入龟头峡
One thing has happened. Yesterday an Ama girl rowed her boat into Ryuzaki.
- 龟头峡？- 那是在本土的一个大山洞
- Ryuzaki? - It is a big cave on the mainland.
当她的船再漂出来时 她已死了
And when her boat floated out again, she was dead.
- 就是我们昨天看到的丧礼？- 是的
- Was that the funeral we saw yesterday? - Yes.
- 她怎么死的？- 没人知道
- How did she die? - Nobody knows.
- 你能带我去山洞吗？- 可以
- Can you take me to this cave? - Yes.
早上我们可以从捕鱼队伍中溜走
We'll slip away from the fishing fleet in the morning.
你还好吧？
All right?
山洞在哪里？
Now, where is this cave?
就在前面 山洞在那里
It's straight across. The cave is over there.
毒气 快到另一边去！
Gas. Get over the side, quick!
用毒气来避免陌生人进入
Phosgene gas, to keep the visitors away.
你有注意到墙上的硫磺吗？
Did you notice the sulfur on the walls?
- 黄色的部分？- 对
- The yellow? - Yes.
那曾是熔岩的地下出口
It was once an underground outlet for the lava from the volcano.
- 那里一定有很长的隧道 - 有好几里
- There must be a long tunnel. - Miles of it.
一直通往上面 直到山顶
It leads all the way, right up to the top there.
我们必须到山上去 你可以吗？
That's where we have to go. Can you make it?
- 当然可以 这是任务 - 很好
- Of course. It's business. - Good.
- 我可以休息一下吗？- 可以
- May I rest a moment? - Surely.
- 很辛苦 - 好一个蜜月
- It's hard work. - Mm. Some honeymoon.
它飞进了火山里
It's going down, into the volcano.
直升机回基地
Heliport to position.
蜜月结束了 走吧
The honeymoon's over. Come on.
- 这是死火山吧？- 一直都是 在我这辈子都是
- This volcano isn't active, is it? - It never has been. Not in my lifetime.
最近这里非常炽热
There's been some terrific heat here recently.
- 那直升机怎么了？- 在下边某个地方
- What happened to the helicopter? - It's down there somewhere.
来吧
Come on.
准备 开始十秒倒数
Stand by. Mark. Stand by for ten-second countdown.
十 九 八…
Ten, nine, eight…
太空船进入轨道后所有单位都进入戒备状态
All units throughout the world will remain at readiness so long as we're in orbit.
三 二 一
…three, two, one.
发射
Ignition.
现在我们只能等候和祈祷
This is it, gentlemen. All we can do now is wait and pray.
- 这里很深吗？- 通常是的
- Is that deep? - They usually are. Very.
是金属的！待在这儿
It's metal! Wait here.
直升机准备起飞
Heliport to takeoff position.
打开火山口
Open crater.
紧急人员就位
Emergency crews to stations.
回去通知田中带所有人来
Get back to Tanaka. Tell him to bring every man he's got.
好的
Yes.
关闭直升机升降台
Heliport to standby position.
太空人到更衣室…
Astronauts to dressing rooms. Astronauts to dressing rooms.
注意 美国目标太空船已在轨道
Attention. Attention. American target vehicle is now in orbit.
两小时后进行截击
Interception will take place in two hours' time.
华府 这里是休士顿 休士顿呼叫华府
Washington, this is Houston. Houston to Washington.
太空船现在的高度是120海里 航行距离是170英里
Our vehicle is now 120 nautical miles altitude, 170 miles downrange.
木星呼叫休士顿 现在进入第二阶段
Jupiter to Houston, we now have second phase.
收到 木星
Roger, Jupiter.
太空船已起飞了四小时三十六分
We are four hours plus 36 minutes into the mission.
- 可否报告时间？- 收到
- Can you give us a time? - Roger.
连接点火装置
Connect igniter cable.
雷达技术人员到控制室报到
Radar technicians, report to control room.
一百分钟后发射 正在倒数
T minus 100 minutes and counting.
你们是自愿参加太空人训练的？
Did you volunteer for astronaut training?
在我国 我们叫做宇宙飞行员 是的 我们两个…
In our country, we say "cosmonaut". Yes, both of us.
我们受训了六个月
Since six months we started training.
你们好
Good evening.
- 你是谁？- 退后 我要炸开门锁
- Who the hell are you? - Stand back, I'm gonna blow the lock.
退后
Stand back.
穿上他们的制服
Get into their uniforms.
太空人有两分钟时间
Astronauts have two minutes.
重复 两分钟
Repeat, two minutes.
后备太空人准备
Reserve astronaut to stand by.
- 瞄准目标太空船 - 瞄准目标太空船
- Lock on target. - Lock on target vehicle.
检查辅助导航系统
Check secondary guidance.
19分钟后发射 正在倒数
Launch time is now T minus 90 minutes and counting.
太空人请到发射台
Astronauts to launching pad.
重复 太空人立刻到发射台
Repeat, astronauts to launching pad immediately.
工作人员到平台上准备
Crews, stand by on gantry. Crews, stand by on gantry.
- 制止那个太空人 带他来见我 - 制止那个太空人！
- Stop that astronaut. Bring him to me. - Stop that astronaut!
- 后备太空人请到发射台 - 后备太空人立刻到发射台
- Summon the reserve astronaut. - Reserve astronaut to launching pad.
重新瞄准目标太空船
Reserve astronaut to launching pad immediately.
电脑刚刚收到…
Re-coordinate with target vehicle.
目标太空船的最新资料
A new update with target vehicle has been received from computers.
七分钟后发射 正在倒数
We now have T minus seven minutes and counting.
你做错了 朋友
You made a mistake, my friend.
没有太空人会拿著空调机 进入太空舱的
No astronaut would enter the capsule carrying his air conditioner.
脱下他的头盔
Remove his helmet.
詹姆斯邦德 让我自我介绍
James Bond. Allow me to introduce myself.
我是恩斯特布露菲尔
I am Ernst Stavro Blofeld.
他们说你在香港被刺杀
They told me you were assassinated in Hong Kong.
没错 这是我的第二条命
Yes, this is my second life.
你只能活两次 邦德
You only live twice, Mr. Bond.
目标太空船正在俄国中部的上空 一直飞向蒙古
Target vehicle passing over central Russia. Approaching Mongolia.
轨道跟预期一样
Track is as predicted.
我快要发动一场小型战争
As you see, I am about to inaugurate a little war.
数小时后 美国跟俄国将会互相摧毁
In a matter of hours, when America and Russia have annihilated each other,
地球将会由新的势力来统治
we shall see a new power dominating the world.
- 目标太空船已进入范围 - 重新检查目标太空船
- Target vehicle on scope. - Brief check on target vehicle.
脱掉他的太空衣 搜他的身
Remove his suit and search him.
后备太空人已经准备妥当
Reserve astronaut ready on Bird 1.
- 准备发射 - 准备发射
- Prepare for firing. - Prepare for firing.
所有人离开发射区
Clear the area.
紧急人员准备
Emergency services to stand by.
所有人已经离开发射区
Area now clear.
一分三十秒后发射 正在倒数
T minus one minute 30 seconds and counting.
重新瞄准目标太空船
Re-coordinate with target vehicle.
飞鸟一号准备妥当
Bird 1 now in readiness.
太空人也准备妥当 所有系统运作正常
Astronauts ready on Bird. All systems are go.
- 关上百叶窗 - 关上百叶窗
- Close shutters. - Close shutters.
- 开始中断雷达讯号 - 中断雷达讯号
- Radar blackout commence. - Radar blackout in operation.
有效范围八百公里
Effective range, kilometers 800.
- 打开火山口 - 打开火山口
- Open crater. - Opening crater.
火山口正在打开
Crater opening.
飞鸟一号准备起飞
Bird 1 to liftoff position.
开动引擎 打开压力箱
Gimbal the engines. Pressurized tanks open.
抽气扇全力开动
Ventilator fans to full power.
十秒 九 八
Ten seconds. Nine. Eight.
七 六 五 四
Seven. Six. Five. Four.
三 二 一
Three. Two. One.
零 开动引擎
Zero. Ignition.
- 关闭火山口 - 正在关闭火山口
- Close crater. - Closing crater.
打开百叶窗
Open shutters.
飞鸟一号呼叫基地 火箭分离成功
Bird 1 to base. Separation complete. Confirm acquisition.
呼叫飞鸟一号
Calling Bird 1.
你现在已飞行了七十海里 高度为二百英里
You are 70 nautical miles downrange, 200 miles altitude.
我们的工作很快就完成
Hans, our job will soon be done.
我们一抓到美国人就引爆太空船
Blow them up as soon as they have captured the Americans.
这是开启爆炸装置的钥匙
Here is the key to operate the exploder button.
有人进入火山口
There are men in the crater. Men in the crater.
- 发射火山口的机关枪 - 发射火山口的机关枪
- Crater guns, fire. - Crater guns, open fire.
火山口的火力足够歼灭一队军队
The firing power inside my crater is enough to annihilate a small army.
你能从荧幕上看到
You can watch it all on TV.
这可能是你看到的最后一个节目
It's the last program you're likely to see.
如果你非得逼我看电视 我能抽烟吗？
If I'm going to be forced to watch television, may I smoke?
可以 把他的香烟给他
Yes. Give him his cigarettes.
你不会是死于尼古丁的
It won't be the nicotine that kills you, Mr. Bond.
武装警卫到控制室
Armed guards to control room.
- 关闭火山口 - 关闭火山口
- Close the crater. - Close crater.
我个人很期望杀了你
I shall look forward personally to exterminating you, Mr. Bond.
关闭百叶窗
Close the shutters.
我们是攻不破的
We are now impregnable.
八分钟后进行截击 没人可以阻止我们了
Interception will take place in eight minutes. Nothing can prevent that.
攻不破的？
Impregnable?
- 跟我来 邦德先生 - 飞鸟一号呼叫基地
- Come with me, Mr. Bond. - Bird 1 to base. Locked on target.
- 瞄准目标 - 是的
- Osato? - Yes, Number One.
基地呼叫飞鸟一号
Base calling Bird 1.
从现在起 你们得负起责任 全力完成行动
You are to assume full control of operation from now on.
- 七分钟后 开始截击太空船 - 收到 基地
- Seven minutes to interception. - Roger, Base One.
夏威夷呼叫休士顿 观测器上出现不明物体
Houston, this is Hawaii. We have an unidentified object on scope.
一级警戒信号 所有武器准备
Order first alert. Arm all weapons.
六分钟后开始截击行动
Interception will occur in six minutes.
这是失败者必须付出的代价 邦德先生
This is the price of failure, Mr. Bond.
走
Come on.
再见 邦德先生！
Goodbye, Mr. Bond!
控制室有个引爆装置 我们必须上去那里
There's an exploder button up in the control room. We've gotta get up there.
不可能 他们防守的太好
Impossible. Too well defended.
撤退控制室
Evacuate the control. Evacuate the control.
控制室的技术人员 一定有其他的路可以上去
Control room technicians. There must be another way up there.
掩护我上阶梯
Give me cover till I get to the staircase.
啊！
Aaargh!
用餐愉快
Bon appit.
渐渐接近我们的太空船 一样的轨道
Closing fast on our vehicle. Orbit identical.
所有人员待命 行动代号是「紧急」
All units stand by for codeword. Codeword is imminent.
重复 渐渐接近我们的太空船
I repeat, closing fast on our vehicle.
敌人爆炸了！重复 敌人已爆炸了！
It's blown up! The enemy! I repeat, the enemy has blown up!
所有单位回到一级警戒
All units will return to first alert.
代号是「不紧急」 我重复「不紧急」
Codeword is "not", I say again, "not imminent".
我们成功了
Tiger, we've done it.
下面！
Down the tunnel!
稳著点
Steady.
关于我们的蜜月
Now, er… about that honeymoon.
为什么不继续？但他们不会让你留下
Why not? But they'll never let you stay.
他们不会找到我们
But they'll never find us.
他已登船了
Dinghy's on board, sir.Tell him to come below and report.
会很愉快的
It'll be a pleasure, sir.